joji_antony@gmx.com +91 96323 41954

Profile

Back end leaning full stack software engineer with 6+ years of professional experience building IT infrastructure software. Proficient in developing beautiful software systems that have very high requirements of stability, security and scale. Deeply committed to usability, maintainability and security. Loves shipping, helping businesses and customers succeed.

Education

Undergraduate College Education

College of Engineering, Trivandrum

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

Technologies

Languages and Frameworks

Python (Flask), C, C++, Java (EE, Hibernate), Javascript (React, Redux), Perl

Tools

Docker, Postgres, MySQL, Jboss, Git, Maven, Linux Containers etc

Platforms

VMWare vSphere, Nutanix Enterprise Cloud, Amazon Web Services, UNIX

Work Experience and Projects

Work Experience Employed by Nutanix since June 2016

Nutanix Xtract Team

2016 - present

Accomplishments

Lead the AHV hypervisor support feature in Nutanix Xtract for DBs

Implemented error handling and remediation of Nutanix X plorer Lead the release of AMF X plorer $1.0\,$

HPE Hyperconverged cloud

2016 - 2016

Front end developer at HPE Hyper converged cloud team

Accomplishments

Implemented Image Management

Technologies

ReactJS, Webpack, Gulp, SASS

HP Network Management Center

2013 - 2016

Worked as a core developer and security engineer for HP's Network Management Software called Network Node Manager i

Also worked as lead developer and lab support engineer for NNMi Network Engineer's

Toolset

Accomplishments

- Improving SNMP v3 USM specification compliance in the SNMP stack
- Enabling Network Function Virtualization support
- Port the Network Engineer's Tool set to Linux
- Add support for Safari on Mac
- Adding CSRF protection to the NNMi
- Released NNMi SPI NET 10.0, 10.10, 10.20, NNMi 10.10 and NNMi 10.20

Technologies

Java EE, JavaScript Dojo framework, Java Swing, etc

HP Network Node Manager 7.x lab support

2011 - 2013

Lab support engineer for Hewlett-Packard's premier Network Management Solution called NNM

Accomplishments

- Solved many multi-threading issues (ACE framework)
- Solved many cache coherence issues
- Released NNM 7.53 Intermediate Patches 31 and 32

Technologies

C, C++, Perl, SQL, Java

Side projects

Plivo Call Center

2015-Present

Functional call center application using Plivo API running on the Heroku Platform https://github.com/simula67/plivo-callcenter

Open source

Perl 6 LWP

Merged a patch to Perl 6 LWP to match output of Perl 5 LWP https://github.com/simula67/perl6-lwp-simple

Perl 6 Test Suite

Merged a patch to re factor some of Perl 6 official test suite https://github.com/simula67/roast

Snaplr packaging for Chocolatey

Packaging Snaplr for chocolatey

https://github.com/simula67/chocolateytemplates

Online Profiles

Blog: https://simula67.wordpress.com about.me: https://about.me/jojiantony